<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>
<plan plan-format="1.0" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      name="modeling.emf.eef">
   <release projectid="modeling.emft.eef" version="1.0.0"/>
   <introduction>
     <html:div>
This document lays out the feature and API set for the 1.0.0 release of the Extended Editing Framework project.
This project plan inherits from the Modeling Project Plan, which should be referenced when consulting this individual project plan.
     </html:div>
   </introduction>
   <release_deliverables>
     <html:div>
The release deliverables have the same form as is found in most Eclipse projects, namely:
       <ul>
         <li>
EEF source code release, available as versions tagged with "R1_0" in the project's CVS repository.
         </li>
         <li>
EEF SDK, which includes runtime, sources, examples, and documentation, and is available as a download or on the update site.
         </li>
         <li>
EEF binary distribution, available as a download or on the update site.
         </li>
         <li>
EEF tests available as a download.
         </li>
       </ul>
     </html:div>
   </release_deliverables>
   <release_milestones>
      <preamble>
         <html:div>
Release milestones occur at roughly 6 week intervals and follow the Platform release milestone by the Indigo-established +2 delta interval. 
The final EEF 1.0.0 release will available simultaneously with the 3.7 release of the Platform and all the other Indigo projects.
         </html:div>
      </preamble>
<milestone date="09/28/2010" milestone="M2"></milestone>
<milestone date="11/09/2010" milestone="M3"></milestone>
<milestone date="12/14/2010" milestone="M4"></milestone>
<milestone date="02/08/2011" milestone="M5"></milestone>
<milestone date="03/15/2011" milestone="M6"><html:div>API freeze</html:div></milestone>
<milestone date="05/03/2011" milestone="M7"><html:div>Feature Freeze</html:div></milestone>
<milestone date="05/17/2011" milestone="RC1"></milestone>
<milestone date="05/24/2011" milestone="RC2"></milestone>
<milestone date="05/31/2011" milestone="RC3"></milestone>
<milestone date="06/07/2011" milestone="RC4"></milestone>
<milestone date="06/22/2011" milestone="Final"></milestone>
    </release_milestones>
    <target_environments>
      <html:div>
In order to remain current, each Eclipse release targets reasonably current versions of the underlying operating environments. 
The EEF project depends upon on the Platform, which is mostly "pure" Java™. The 3.7 release of the Eclipse Platform Project 
is written and compiled against version 1.5 of the Java Platform APIs, and targeted to run on version 1.5 of the Java Runtime Environment, Standard Edition. 
EEF rely on EMF Core which is written and compiled against version 1.5 of the Java Platform APIs., EEF relies on Java 5. 
Eclipse Platform SDK 3.7 will be tested and validated on a number of reference platforms. EEF will be tested and validated against a subset of those listed for the platform.

Given that there is no operating system dependent code in EEF, it's expected that EEF will work anywhere the Eclipse Platform does.
     </html:div>
     <internationalization>
          <html:div>
The Eclipse Platform is designed as the basis for internationalized products. The user interface elements provided by the Eclipse SDK components, including dialogs and error messages,
are externalized. The English strings are provided as the default resource bundles. Similarly, the EEF project will externalize all its user interface elements,
provide English strings for them in its default bundles, and localize a subset of the locales offered by the Platform. The download page will provide the details as the become available.
          </html:div>
     </internationalization>
   </target_environments>
   <themes_and_priorities>
     <preamble>
         <html:div>
A list of project goals and agreed upon implementation time frames is found in this document. For the milestones listed in this document, a set of overall themes is used to 
indicate what major set of functionalities is expected to be the focus of each. These themes are presented below, while the goals of the associated Bugzilla entries are available 
for more detailed information.
  </html:div>
     </preamble>
       <theme name="EEF Editor modeling and generation">
            <description>
                <html:div>
                EEF will provide a modeling environment and a generation module allow users to build form editors. These editors use EEF specifics viewer to edit elements properties. 
                </html:div>
            </description>
        </theme>
        <theme name="EMF.edit integration">
            <description>
                <html:div>
                The EEF runtime will be redesign in order to be more with EMF.edit framework API.  
                </html:div>
            </description>
        </theme>
        <theme name="EMF code generation with Acceleo">
            <description>
                <html:div>
                EEF will provide a example Acceleo module allowing EMF user to generate model, edit and editor from an EMF generation model.  
                </html:div>
            </description>
        </theme>
   </themes_and_priorities>
   <appendix name="Legal Notices">
        <html:div>
          <ul>
            <li>
Java is a trademark or a registered trademark of Sun Microsystems, Inc.
            </li>
            <li>
All other products or company names are mentioned for identification purposes only,
and may be trademarks or service marks of their respective owners.
            </li>
          </ul>
        </html:div>
   </appendix>
</plan>
